I'm voting for Dukakis.
Hmm.
Well.
Maybe when you have children
of your own who need braces,
and you can't afford them because
half your husband's paycheck
goes to the federal government,
- you'll regret that.
- My "husband's paycheck"?
Anyway, I'm not gonna squeeze
one out till I'm, like, 30.
Will you still be working at the Yarn
Barn? Because I hear it's a really
- great place to raise children.
- That's really funny.
No, a year of partying's enough.
She'll be going to Harvard next fall.
Mum, I haven't even gotten in yet.
You honestly think Dukakis will provide for
this country till you squeeze one out?
Yeah. I do.
- Can I squeeze one out?
- Not till eighth grade.
Excuse me.
Donnie, you're such a dick.
Whoa, Elizabeth.
A little hostile there.
Mum and Dad should pay a therapist
$200 an hour to listen to you
so we don't have to.
OK. Wanna tell Mum and Dad why
you stopped taking your medication?
- You're such a fuck-ass.
- What?!
- Please.
- Did he call me a fuck-ass?
- Hey, Sweetie.
- That's enough.
- You can go suck a fuck.
- How does one do that?
- Want me to tell you?
- Please, tell me.
We will not have this
at the dinner table.
Stop!
What's a fuck-ass?
I'm reading.
Get out of my room.
Where do you go at night?
Will you just get out of my room?
Did you toilet-paper
the Johnsons' house?
- You came to ask me that?
- No.
I stopped rolling houses
in sixth grade, Mum.
What happened to my son?
I don't recognise this person today.
Then why don't you start
taking the goddamn pills!
Bitch.
Our son just called me a bitch.
You're not a bitch.
You're bitching, but you're not a bitch.
'I want to be a president of
the Unites States who makes sure
'we never again do business
with a Panamanian dictator.
- 'That we never again funnel aid...'
- Dukakis.
- Son of a bitch.
- 'Panama is a friendly country.
- 'I talked to Panama's president...'
- Tell him, George!
'...about cleaning up
their money-laundering.
'Mr Noriega was there,
but there was no evidence...'
'Wake up.
'I've been watching you.
'Come closer.
'Closer.'
28 days,
six hours,
42 minutes,
12 seconds.
That is when the world will end.
Why?
Son?
Son? Donnie Darko?
Donnie Darko?
- What the heck's going on?
- Who is it, Don?
It's Eddie Darko's kid. I'm sorry
about this. He's just a neighbourhood kid.
Guess he was sleep-golfing.
Watch out for that drool spot.
Are you all right, son?
So...
Let's stay off the links at night, OK?
I'm sorry, Dr Fisher.
It won't happen again.
- I hate kids.
- Let's golf.
Donnie! Donnie! Donnie!
What happened to your house?
- No-one's allowed through...
- This is my house!
He's OK.
Donnie, we know you're OK!
Channel 6 News.
We have just arrived on the scene...
Wait a minute. Here's your brother.
- Oh!
- It fell in your room.
Watch yourself down there!
Mrs Darko?
I'm Bob Garland. I'm with the FAA.
- You're what?
- I'm with the FAA.
If you don't mind, we'd like to speak
to you and Mr Darko privately.
- In private?
- Please.
All right.
You see that little red thing in there?
And... here.
- You got it.
- All right.
We have arranged for you
to stay at a hotel, get some sleep.
- We will take care of things here.
- Thank you.
Kids, we're going to a hotel.
They don't know where it came from.
'Transportation
authorities have begun a search...'
Frankie Feedler.
'...no airline will claim ownership...'
You remember him?
From high school.
Hmm.
He died.
- On his way to the prom.
- Mm.
- Remember?
- Mm-hm.
They said he was doomed.
Mm.
Jesus.
They could have said the same thing
about Donnie.
If it fell from a plane,
then what happened to the plane?
They don't know, Samantha.
Mrs Farmer will bring you home
after practice. Bye, honey.
Donnie. Good luck.
Oh, my God.
OK, tell me everything.
- I'm not allowed to talk about it.
- Oh, my God.
- Hi, Cherita.
- Shut up.
Darko cheats death, uh?
You're like a celebrity, man.
I've been calling you a gillion times.
Where you been?
We stayed at a hotel.
My dad saw you at the golf course.
You sleepwalking again now buddy?
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- Now you're famous, have a smoke.
What happens if you tell
Mum and Dad about this, Sam?
You'll put Ariel
in the garbage disposal.
- Goddamn right I will.
- So grody.
Hey, Cherita. You want a cigarette?
- Shut up!
Go back to China, bitch.
Just leave her alone.
Some good shit, huh?
It's a fucking cigarette.
"There would be headlines
in the papers.
"Even the guys who ran the betting
at the wrestling
"and the barrow boys
would hear with respect
"how Old Misery's house
had been destroyed.
"It was as though this plan
had been with him all his life,
"pondered through the seasons,
"now in his 15th year crystallised
with the pain of puberty."
What is Graham Greene trying
to communicate with this passage?
Why did the children break into
Old Misery's house?
- Joanie?
- They wanted to rob him.
Joanie, if you had actually
read the short story,
which at a whooping 13 pages
would have kept you up all night,
you would know that the children find a
great deal of money in the mattress,
but they burn it.
Donnie Darko,
perhaps with your recent brush
with mass destruction
you can give us your opinion.
Well, they say when they flood
the house and tear it to shreds
that destruction is a form of creation,
so the fact that they burn the money
is ironic.
They just want to see what happens
when they tear the world apart.
They wanna change things.
May we help you?
I just registered. They put me
in the wrong English class.
You look like you belong here.
Um, where do I sit?
Sit next to the boy
you think is the cutest.
Quiet. Let her choose.
Joanie, get up.
Well, the construction guys
say it'll take a week to fix the roof.
That airline better not fuck us
on the shingle match.
- They still don't know?
- Know what?
Where it came from.
No. Apparently they can't tell us
what happened yet.
Something about a matching
serial number that got burned.
I had to sign a form saying
I wouldn't talk to anyone about it.
We're not supposed to tell anyone
what nobody knows?
Yeah.
But you tell...
What's your doctor's name?
- Dr Thurman, Dad.
- Yes.
You tell Dr Thurman
whatever you want.
- Dad.
- What?
Dad!
No mail today. Maybe tomorrow.
Well, what did she say to you?
- I made a new friend.
- Real or imaginary?
Imaginary.
Would you like to talk
about this friend?
- Frank.
- What did Frank say?
- He said to follow him.
- Follow him where?
- Into the future.
And then what happens?
And then he said...
Then he said the world
is coming to an end.
Do you think
it's coming to an end?
No.
That's stupid.
'For my entire life
I was a victim of my own fear.'
'Love.'
'I was feeding fear through food.'
'Fear.'
'And finally I looked in the mirror.
'Not just in the mirror.
I looked through the mirror.
'In that image
I saw my ego reflection.'
'I thought ten-year-olds
normally wet the bed...'
Shh!
'The solution was there all the time.'
'I'm not afraid any more!'
'All over America, people have
come together to join hands.
'People who believe that human life
is absolutely too important,
'too valuable and too precious
to be controlled by fear.
'Hello.
'My name is Jim Cunningham.
Welcome to "Controlling Fear."'
'Wake up, Donnie.'
"And the prince was led into a world
of strange and beautiful magic."
Hey, guess what!
I can't believe it!
The school is closed today
because it's flooded.
- No way.
- Yeah.
Holy shit! That's the best news
I've ever heard.
My God. Is this ever gonna stop?
Eventually, yes. But I've got
12 classrooms full of water,
all coming from a busted water main.
- What else?
- What else?!
Principal Cole, I'll show you what else.
That's unbelievable.
That's solid bronze, isn't it?
How did this happen?
The boys' locker room was flooded.
They found faeces everywhere.
- What are faeces?
- Baby mice.
Hey.
Has anyone ever told you
that you're sexy?
I like your boobs.
Hey.
School's cancelled.
Do you want to walk me home?
Sure.
- Don't look so freaked.
- I'm not.
Check your backpack.
Those guys love to steal shit.
- So, why did you move here?
- My parents got a divorce.
My mum had to get a restraining order
against my stepdad.
- He has emotional problems.
- Me too. What kind does he have?
He stabbed my mum
four times in the chest.
Oh. Did he go to jail?
No, he fled. They still can't find him,
but my mum and I had to change our names.
I thought Gretchen Ross was cool.
I was in jail once.
I mean... I accidentally
burned down this house.
It was abandoned, but still...
I got held back in school,
I can't drive till I'm 21, you know.
But I'm over all of that. I...
I'm painting and stuff. Writing.
I want to be a writer. Maybe a painter,
I don't know. Maybe both.
I'll write a book and draw the pictures.
Then maybe people will
understand me. Change things.
Donnie Darko?
What the hell kind of name is that?
It's like some sort of superhero.
What makes you think I'm not?
Look, I should go.
For Physics, Monnitoff wants me
to write this essay.
Greatest invention
ever to benefit mankind.
If it's Monnitoff, that's easy.
Antiseptics.
The whole sanitation thing.
Joseph Lister, 1895.
Before antiseptics
there was no sanitation.
- Especially in medicine.
- You mean soap?
I'm really glad
school was flooded today.
Why's that?
You and I would never
have had this conversation.
You're weird.
Sorry.
No, that was a compliment.
Well, look, um...
You wanna go with me?
Where do you wanna go?
I mean, like, go with me. You know...
That's what we call it here.
- Going together...
- Sure.
OK. Where are you going?
I'm going home.
So stupid! Where are you going?
I'd like to try something new this time.
Have you ever been hypnotised?
No.
When I clap my hands twice, you
will wake up. Do you understand?
Yes.
So, tell me about your week.
I met a girl.
- What is her name?
- Gretchen.
We're going together now.
Do you still think about girls a lot?
Yeah.
How are things going at school?
I think about girls a lot.
I asked you about school, Donnie.
I think about fucking
a lot during school.
What else do you think about
during school?
- "Married With Children."
- Do you think about your family?
I just turn down the volume and think
about fucking Christina Applegate.
I asked you about your family,
Donnie.
No.
I don't think about fucking my family.
That's gross.
I'd like to hear
about your friend Frank.
Sam Bylen.
Donald Darko.
Daye Dennis.
Hey, you fuck.
Did you tell them I flooded the school?
- I didn't say shit.
- They think I did it.
If you're innocent, then
you have nothing to worry about.
Fuck you!
You know what I think?
I think you did it.
Beer and pussy. That's all I need.
We gotta find ourselves a Smurfette.
- Smurfette?
- Mm-hm.
Not some tight-assed
Middlesex chick.
A cute little blonde that'll get
down and dirty with the guys.
- Like Smurfette does.
- Smurfette doesn't fuck.
Smurfette fucks the other smurfs.
Why did Papa Smurf make her?
Because all the other smurfs
were getting too horny.
Not Vanity.
I heard he was a homosexual.
OK, she fucks them
while Vanity watches. OK?
What about Papa Smurf?
He must get in on the action.
Yeah. When he does, he films the gangbang.
Later on, he beats off to the tape.
First of all, Papa Smurf didn't create
Smurfette. Gargamel did.
She was sent in as Gargamel's evil spy,
to destroy the smurf village.
But the overwhelming goodness
of the smurf way of life transformed her.
And as for
the whole gangbang scenario,
it just couldn't happen.
Smurfs are asexual.
They don't even have...
reproductive organs
under those little white pants.
That's what's so illogical, you know,
about being a smurf.
What's the point of living
if you don't have a dick?
Dammit, Donnie, why you gotta get
so smart on us?
Grandma Death.
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Stay off the road, Miss Sparrow.
I'll have to call social services.
I hate that Miss Farmer.
She's such a fucking bitch.
Yeah.
- How old is Grandma Death?
- 101.
She does the same thing every day.
Just walks back and forth,
back and forth to the mailbox.
And nothing ever in there.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
She's going back to the box.
We may still have mail.
- Mail, mail, mail.
- Here it is.
This could be it. Oh!
No dice, Grandma.
No, sorry.
Someone ought to write that bitch.
'Authorities
continued their search
'for a suspect
in the school vandalism.
'The school has asked for donations
to help restore its mascot,
'known only as the Mongrel.'
In cooperation with the county police,
we have begun investigating
the cause of the flooding
and our suspects include
several of our own students.
I want to know why this filth
is being taught to our children.
Kitty, I would appreciate
if you would wait...
Dr Cole, not only am I a teacher,
but I am also a parent
of a Middlesex child.
Therefore, I am the only person here who
transcends the parent-teacher bridge.
'Don't worry.
'You got away with it.'
I have in my hand
Graham Greene's "The Destructors."
This short story is part of
my daughter's English assignment.
In this story, several children
destroy an elderly man's house
from inside out.
How can you do that?
And how do they do this?
They flood the house
by breaking through a water main.
'I can do anything I want.
'And so can you.'
We pay good money for this school
It's our children.
And I think that this garbage
should be removed.
Excuse me.
What's the real issue here?
The PTA doesn't ban books.
The PTA is here to acknowledge
that pornography is being taught.
- It's meant to be ironic.
- You need to go back to grad school.
Why did you make me
flood the school?
They are in great danger.
Kitty, do you even know
who Graham Greene is?
I think we have all seen "Bonanza."
Well, uh...
while we are on other topics...
Where did you come from?
Do you believe in time travel?
Who are you talking to?
I was just taking my pills, Sam.
'It is time to breathe.'
'Thank you, Jim Cunningham.'
'So, now let us begin
lifeline exercise No.1.
'Please press stop now.'
As you can see, the lifeline is divided
into two polar extremes.
Fear and love.
Fear is in
the negative energy spectrum
and love is in
the positive energy spectrum.
- Duh!
- Excuse me?
"Duh" is a product of fear.
Now, on each card
is a character dilemma
which applies to the lifeline.
Please... Take this.
Thank you.
Please read
each character dilemma aloud
and place an X on the lifeline
in the appropriate place.
Cherita?
"Juanita has an important math test
today.
"She has known about the test for
several weeks but has not studied.
"In order to keep from failing her class,
"Juanita decides that she will cheat
on the math test."
Good. Good. Very good.
Um, Mr Darko.
"Ling Ling finds a wallet
on the ground, filled with money.
"She takes the wallet to the address
inside but keeps the money."
I'm sorry, Miss Farmer.
I don't get this.
Just place an X on the lifeline
in the appropriate place.
No, I know what to do. I don't get this.
You can't lump things
into two categories.
The lifeline is divided that way.
Well, life isn't that simple.
Who cares if Ling Ling returns
the wallet and keeps the money?
It has nothing to do with
either fear or love.
Fear and love
are the deepest of human emotions.
OK. But you're not listening to me.
There are other things that need
to be taken into account here.
Like the whole spectrum
of human emotion.
You can't lump everything into two
categories and deny everything else.
If you don't complete the assignment,
you'll get a zero for the day.
Donald.
Let me preface this by saying
that your Iowa Test scores
are... intimidating.
So... let's go over this again.
What exactly did you say
to Mrs Farmer?
I'll tell you what he said.
He asked me to forcibly insert
the lifeline exercise card into my anus.
These are modern times.
My political attitudes are forthright.
If there's a vice presidential candidate
worthy of my vote, it has to be Dan Quayle.
Nobody cares about responsibility,
morality, family values...
Kitty...
Excuse us, please.
They've suspended him from after-school
activities for the next six months.
Ever since this jet engine fiasco
I don't know what's gotten into him.
Rose, our daughters have been on
the dance team together for two years
and I respect you as a woman.
But after witnessing your son's
behaviour, I have doubts about your...
Our paths through life
must be righteous.
I urge you to go home
and look in the mirror,
and pray that your son
doesn't succumb to the path of fear.
Do you remember
that weird gym teacher Mrs Farmer?
Yeah.
OK, my brother told her to shove
a book up her ass today.
And then my parents just bought him
all this new shit.
I know. I wish a jet engine
would fall in my room.
'I can show you the way.'
Yeah.
- Dr Monnitoff?
- Donnie.
Um, I know this is gonna sound
kinda weird, but uh...
do you know anything
about time travel?
Ah! A wormhole
with an Einstein-Rosen bridge,
which is theoretically a wormhole
in space controlled by man.
So, according to Hawking,
a wormhole may be able
to provide a short cut
for jumping between
two distant regions of space time.
So in order to travel
back in time,
you have to have a big spaceship
that can travel faster than light.
- Theoretically.
- And be able to find a wormhole.
The basic principles
of time travel are there.
You've got your vessel and your portal,
and your vessel can be
just about anything. Probably a spacecraft.
- Like a DeLorean.
- Any metal craft.
I love that movie, the way they shot it.
It's so... like futuristic, you know.
Listen... don't tell anybody
that I gave you this.
The woman who wrote this
used to teach here.
She was a nun
many years before that.
Then overnight she became
this entirely different person.
She up and left the church,
she wrote this book.
She started teaching science.
Right here in Middlesex.
"The Philosophy of Time Travel."
Roberta Sparrow?
That's right.
Come on.
Roberta Sparrow.
Roberta Sparrow...
Grandma Death.
It's called
"The Philosophy of Time Travel."
What does philosophy
have to do with time travel?
- Let me see.
- Guess who wrote it.
Roberta Sparrow?
Huh! She wrote a book!
Grandma Death wrote a book.
That's a terrible nickname.
We almost hit her with the car
the other day.
She lives in that piece of crap house
and you know she's loaded.
- She's...
- You're right.
She used to be known
for her gem collection.
Kids... used to go up there
and try to steal stuff from her.
She became a total recluse.
I didn't know she was alive
till we damn near knocked her down.
She was standing
in the road, frozen,
so I got out of the car and
walked over to see if she was OK.
She leaned over
and whispered in my ear.
- What did she say?
- Frank wants me to talk to her.
He asked me
if I knew about time travel.
She wrote a book about it,
so it can't be like a coincidence, right?
Donnie, what did
Roberta Sparrow say to you?
She said every living creature
on earth dies alone.
How did that make you feel?
It reminded me of my dog Callie.
She died when I was eight and...
she crawled underneath the porch.
To die?
To be alone.
Do you feel alone right now?
I mean, I'd like to believe I'm not,
but I just...
I've just never seen any proof, so I...
I just don't debate it any more,
you know.
I could spend my whole life
debating it over and over again,
weighting the pros and cons
and I still wouldn't have any proof,
so I just...
I just don't debate it any more.
It's absurd.
The search for God is absurd?
It is if everyone dies alone.
Does that scare you?
I don't want to be alone.
And so, his tapes
have made me realise
that for the last 39 years I have been
a prisoner of my own fear.
Fear?
Rose, you have got to meet
this Jim Cunningham.
I can't believe he's single.
'It has been a disappointing night
for these Super Bowl champions.
'Coach Joe Gibbs is on the sidelines,
water dripping off his glasses.
'He's gotta be thinking,
"What went wrong tonight?"
'Here's the kick.'
'And it's no good.'
We need a quarterback.
And a miracle.
We need to go for a safety.
'Mark Rypien certainly
has some big shoes to fill.
'He sure does.'
You guys want anything?
I'm gonna get a beer.
'Good evening,
ladies and ghouls.
'Join us at the Middlesex pavilion hall
'for the Middlesex Halloween Haunt.
What if you could go back in time
and take all the pain and darkness
and replace it with something better?
- Images?
- Yeah. Like a Hawaiian sunset
or the Grand Canyon. Things
that remind you how beautiful...
You know, we've been going together
for like, two weeks.
Yeah.
Well, I uh...
Do you wanna kiss me?
Uh...
- I... Sorry...
- Donnie, wait. I just...
I just want it to be at a time when it...
- When what?
- When it reminds me... just...
When it reminds you how beautiful
the world can be?
Yeah.
And right now there's some fat guy
over there staring at us.
Thank you for seeing us
at such late notice.
We both felt it was time for us
to come in and discuss...
What I think is going on
with your son?
Yes.
Um... Well, he's uh...
You know about his past,
and he was suspended from school
for insulting his gym teacher.
I'm not sure that's a good example.
He had just cause to insult...
Rose, let me just lay out
what I believe is happening here.
Donnie's aggressive behaviour,
his increased detachment
from reality,
seem to stem
from his inability to cope
with the forces in the world
that he perceives to be threatening.
Has he ever told you
about his friend Frank?
Frank?
The giant bunny rabbit.
What?
I don't recall him
ever having mentioned a rabbit.
Donnie is experiencing what is
commonly called a daylight hallucination.
This is a common occurrence
among paranoid schizophrenics.
What can we do?
I would like to do more hypnotherapy.
And increase his medication.
Whatever will help him, really,
because that's why we're here.
We just would like him
to experience some... relief.
So if you think that
more medication will do that,
then I think we should give it a try.
Donnie Darko.
I know.
- Good morning, you Mongrels.
- Good morning.
Is that all the gusto you can muster?
I said good morning!
Good morning.
Now, that's a tiny, tiny bit better.
But I can still sense some students
who are afraid to say good morning.
Good morning!
That's what I like to hear!
Entirely too many
young men and women today
are completely paralysed
by their fears.
They surrender their bodies
to the temptation and destruction
of drugs, alcohol and premarital sex.
Now, I'm gonna tell you
a little story today.
It's a heartbreakingly sad story
about a young man
whose life was completely destroyed
by these instruments of fear.
A young man searching for love
in all the wrong places.
His name was Frank.
Um, my stepsister... I sometimes
worry that she eats too much.
- Shut up, Kim.
- Sweetheart, please.
- What can I do when I grow up?
- That's a hard one.
What do I do to learn
how to fight?
"What do I do to learn
how to fight?"
Son, violence is a product of fear.
- Learn to truly love yourself.
- Get yourself up here.
All right.
- Good morning.
Um, how much are they paying you
to be here?
Excuse me?
What is your name, son?
Gerald.
Gerald, I think you're afraid.
Are you telling us this so we buy your
book? It's the worst advice I heard.
You see how sad this is?
Want your sister to lose weight? Tell
her to get off the couch and exercise.
No-one knows what to do
when they grow up.
It takes a while to find that out.
Right, Jim?
And you.
Yeah, you.
You sick of some jerk shoving
your head down the toilet?
Maybe you should lift weights
or take a karate lesson.
Next time he tries to do it,
you kick him in the balls.
Son.
Do you see this?
This is an anger prisoner.
A textbook example.
You see the fear, people?
This boy is scared
to death of the truth.
Son, it breaks my heart to say this,
but I believe you are a very troubled
and confused young man.
I believe, you were searching
for the answers in the wrong places.
You're right, actually. I am pretty
troubled and pretty confused.
And I'm afraid.
Really afraid. Really afraid.
But I think you're
the fucking Antichrist.
Get him out of here!
Who do you think you are?
It's amazing.
The man thinks he's telling the truth.
Everything he says is just a fucking lie.
Everything he says.
Everyone thinks he's so rad.
He's such a chud.
- Everything he does...
- Are you OK?
- Yeah...
- Sit down. Calm down.
You ever hear of Grandma Death?
Who?
"The Philosophy of Time Travel."
What is this?
She wrote it.
I'm...
I've been seeing stuff.
Like a lot of really messed-up stuff.
Chapters in there describe what
I've seen. It can't just be a coincidence.
Each vessel travels
along a vector through space time,
along its centre of gravity.
Like a spear?
- I beg your pardon?
- A spear coming out of your chest.
Um... sure, yeah.
And in order for the vessel
to travel through time,
it's got to find a portal,
in this case a wormhole...
Could these portals just appear
anywhere, any time?
I think that's highly unlikely.
What you're talking about
is an act of God.
If God controls time,
then all time's pre-decided.
- I'm not following you.
- Every living thing has a set path.
And if you could see
your path or channel,
you could see into the future.
Like... a form of time travel.
You're contradicting yourself, Donnie.
If we were able to see our destinies
manifest themselves visually,
then we would be given a choice
to betray our chosen destinies.
The fact that this choice exists
would make all pre-formed destiny
come to an end.
Not if you travel within God's channel.
Um... I'm not going to be able
to continue this conversation.
- Why?
- I could lose my job.
OK.
'Now you know where he lives.'
And they grow out of our chest...
solar plexus?
Like she described in the book.
The way they moved and smelled...
Like they're workers.
Assigned to each one of us.
They just... They're like liquid.
I followed it...
into my parents' bedroom.
What did you find?
Nothing.
So we call them IMGs.
Infant Memory Generators.
So you buy the glasses for an infant
and they wear them when they sleep.
But inside the glasses
are these slide photographs,
and each one is of something
peaceful or beautiful,
whatever the parents want
to put inside.
What effect would this have
on an infant?
Well, nobody remembers
their infancy.
Anyone who says they do is lying.
We think this'll develop memory
earlier in life.
Yeah.
Did you consider that darkness is part
of infants' natural development?
No.
Yeah.
What if the parents
put in pictures of Satan?
Dead people, crap like that.
Is that what you'd show your kids?
Uh, well, I mean... didn't your dad, like,
stab your mum?
Ha ha ha ha!
Get out.
Gretchen!
Gretchen. Gretchen.
I'm sorry about those guys.
- Two for "Evil Dead," please.
- Two dollars.
Why do you wear
that stupid bunny suit?
Why are you wearing
that stupid man's suit?
Take it off.
What happened to your eye?
I'm so sorry.
Why do they call you Frank?
It's the name of my father
and his father before me.
Frank?
When's this gonna stop?
You should already know that.
I want you to
watch the movie screen.
There's something
I want to show you.
Have you ever seen a portal?
Burn it to the ground.
OK. Now, girls,
I want you to concentrate.
Failure is not an option.
Bethany, if you feel the need
to vomit up there,
- just swallow it.
Hey, you guys.
Good luck out there.
Get off the stage, Cherita!
You suck!
Hold on.
That was really something.
Thank you, Cherita Chen,
with "Autumn Angel."
Now the moment
we've all been waiting for.
It is my distinct pleasure
to introduce to you
Emily Bates, Suzy Bailey,
Samantha Darko, Beth Farmer
and Joanie James.
They are... Sparkle Motion.
All right! Sparkle Motion!
How long was I asleep for?
Whole movie.
Captain, looks like we got
another room back here.
'The blaze was
extinguished sometime after 8pm.
'Firefighters discovered what has
been called a "kiddie porn dungeon."
'Cunningham, who has become
a celebrity for his books and tapes,
'was arrested this morning...'
Oh, my God!
'Arson has not been ruled out
as part of the cause of the fire.
'A group of
Cunning Vision employees...'
Dad played golf with that guy.
'...denied alleged links to a child
pornography publishing circuit.
'In a vicious statement, Cunningham
attacked fire department officials,
'claiming a vast conspiracy.'
Karen, we don't think the
methods you've used are appropriate.
What exactly about my methods
do you find inappropriate?
I don't have time to get
into a debate about this, Karen.
I believe I've made myself clear.
You call this clarity?
You don't have a clue what it's like
to communicate with these kids.
And we are losing them to apathy.
To this prescribed nonsense.
They're slipping away.
I am sorry that you have failed.
If you'll excuse me,
I have another appointment.
You can finish out the week.
Fuck!
Good afternoon.
It gives me great pleasure to
announce that the school dance team
has been invited to perform
on Ed McMahon's "Star Search '88"
in Los Angeles, California.
No, it was ridiculous...
I'll call you back.
- Rose.
- Kitty.
I'm sure you're aware of the horrible
allegations against Jim Cunningham.
I know, I saw it on TV.
Something about a kiddie porn...
Oh, please! Don't use those words!
It's obviously a conspiracy
to destroy an innocent man.
I am going to spearhead the
Jim Cunningham defence campaign.
Rose, I have to appear
at his arraignment tomorrow morning.
The girls are scheduled to leave
for Los Angeles in the morning.
As their coach, I was the
obvious choice to chaperone them...
But now you can't go.
- Yes.
- Hm.
Now, believe me,
of all the other mothers,
I would never dream of asking you.
But none of the other mothers
are available to go.
I don't know, Kitty.
It's a bad weekend.
Eddie's in New York.
Rose, I don't know if you realise
what an opportunity this is
for our daughters.
This has been a dream of Samantha's
and all of ours for a long time.
I made her lead dancer.
Sometimes I doubt your commitment
to Sparkle Motion.
Elizabeth will be in charge.
She'll drive you to therapy.
And if you need anything, promise me
you will call Dr Thurman.
How does it feel
to have a wacko for a son?
It feels wonderful.
What do I tell the others
when they ask about you?
Tell them everything
is gonna be just fine.
What's "cellar door"?
This famous linguist once said
that of all the phrases
in the English language,
of all the endless combinations
of words in all of history,
that "cellar door" is the most beautiful.
"Cellar door"?
I promise that one day
everything's gonna be better for you.
Shut up!
- I want to talk about your past today.
- No.
I want to talk
about you and your parents.
They didn't buy me
what I wanted for Christmas.
What did you want for Christmas
that year?
Hungry Hungry Hippos.
How did you feel, being denied
these Hungry Hungry Hippos?
Regret.
What else makes you feel regret?
That I did it again.
You did it again?
I flooded my school and I
burned down that pervert's house.
I only have a few days
before they catch me.
Did Frank tell you to do these things?
I have to obey him. He saved my life.
I have to obey him
or I'll be left all alone,
and then...
and then I won't be able to figure out
what this is all about.
I won't be able
to know his master plan.
Do you mean God's master plan?
Do you now believe in God?
I have the power
to build a time machine.
How is that possible?
How is time travel possible, Donnie?
Time's up, Frank said.
When is this going to happen?
Soon.
What is going to happen?
Frank is gonna kill.
Who is he going to kill?
- Who is he going to kill?
- I can see him right now!
The sky is going to open up.
If the sky were to suddenly open up,
there would be no law.
There would be no rule.
There would only be you
and your memories.
The choices you've made
and the people you've touched.
If this world were to end,
there would only be you and him.
And no-one else.
Hey.
I got in.
I am going to Harvard.
We should totally throw a party.
Mum and Dad are gone. It's
Halloween. We could get away with it.
OK, but it has to be small, all right?
Happy Halloween!
Beelzebub!
We got eggs, water balloons
and a dozen rolls of toilet paper.
I stole four beers from my dad.
- We got a keg.
- Keg beer is for pussies.
'Rose, this is Lilian Thurman.
It is extremely important that you
call me as soon as you hear this.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Hey.
You OK?
Yeah. My mum's gone.
You wanna come in?
Yeah.
I don't know. She...
She didn't leave a note and...
the house was all messed up.
But you're OK?
Did you call the cops?
Yeah. They said I should leave
the house and go to a safe place.
I'm just so scared. I keep thinking
something awful is happening and...
It's my fucking stepdad. I know it.
I guess some people are just
born with tragedy in their blood.
- Have you guys seen Frank?
- No, I think they went on a beer run.
'If you're there, pick up.
'Hello. Good news.
The girls got three and a half stars
'and get to come back
for the quarterfinals.
'Samantha was amazing. Anyway...
We'll take the red-eye back tonight,
and we...
Mum, the plane's about to leave.
We'll take the red-eye
and should arrive around 8.30.
Um... I hope everything's all right.
I love you. Bye.
'Cellar door.'
- Come with me.
- Where are we going?
- Just tell me.
- Look, we gotta go.
- We have to see Grandma Death.
- Is this about the book?
No, it's Frank. Time is running out.
We gotta go.
Roberta Sparrow.
Grandma Death.
Donnie, nobody's here.
Let's forget about it.
Cellar door.
What?
Donnie!
Why the fuck are you here?
Oh, my God.
- You're dead!
- What do we do with him?
Leave him alone!
Don't fucking move.
Oh, fuck! Aargh!
There's a car!
Get the hell out of here! Now!
Seth, there's a car coming! Let's go!
- I have a bigger knife now.
- God!
Let's go! Here come the cops!
Did you call the fucking cops?
- Deus ex machina.
- What did you say?
- What the fuck did you say?
- Our saviour.
Donnie!
Gretchen?
Gretchen.
Wake up, Gretchen.
Frank.
- Wake up.
- What did you do?
Gretchen, wake up. Wake up.
Wake up.
Gretchen?
Gretchen.
What the fuck did you do, man?
You killed her, Frank!
Is she dead?
What were you guys doing
in the road?
What were you thinking?
Go home!
Go home and tell your parents
everything'll be OK.
Go!
'28 days,
'six hours...'
42 minutes,
12 seconds.
I'm going home.
'To travel back in time,
'you have to have a spaceship
that can travel faster than light.'
- 'Theoretically.'
- 'And be able to find a wormhole.'
'The principles of time travel are
there. You've got a vessel, a portal.
'The vessel can be anything.
Probably a spacecraft.
'A metal craft of any kind.'
'What if you could go back in time
'and take all those hours
of pain and darkness
'and replace them
with something better?'
'Dear Roberta Sparrow,
'I've reached you in your book
'and there's so many things
I need to ask you.
'Sometimes I'm afraid
of what you might tell me.
'Sometimes I'm afraid you'll tell me
this is not a work of fiction.
'I can only hope the answers
will come to me in my sleep.
'I hope that when the world
comes to an end,
'I can breathe a sigh of relief
'because there will be so much
to look forward to.'
Hey.
What's going on?
Horrible accident.
My neighbour... got killed.
What happened?
Got smooshed by a jet engine.
What was his name?
Donnie. Donnie Darko.
Hmm.
I feel bad for his family.
Yeah.
Did you know him?
No.